Speaker 1: CNN has learned that President Trump attempted to persuade two of the nation's top intelligence officials to issue public statements knocking down the probe into possible collusion between the Trump campaign and Russia. Joining us now are lawmakers from
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): both parties. We have Representative Pramila Jayapal. She's a Democrat on the Judiciary Committee and Representative Jim Banks. He's a Republican from Indiana. He's on the Armed Services Committee. Thanks very much to both of you. Bipartisan show of support tonight for us. If I could begin with you, Congresswoman, what's your reaction
to
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): to our reporting, as first reported by the Washington Post tonight, that President Trump made calls to Admiral Mike Rogers, Dan Coats, the director of national intelligence, in effect, asking them to knock down evidence in this investigation. I think
Speaker 3: it's incredibly troubling. I think it continues a stream of events. I feel a little bit like I have whiplash going from one story to the next. But all of them point to this president trying to interfere with an investigation. And I think that's extremely disturbing.
Speaker 3: that we are looking to try to get to the bottom of this. Obviously, there's the special counsel investigation, but we also in Congress have authority over these matters. And so the question, and I think you were discussing it earlier, is what kind of information can we get as we start to look into all of these
issues?
Speaker 3: You use the word
Speaker 4: interference. Is it obstruction of justice?
I
Speaker 3: think if it's true, I do believe it's obstruction of justice.
We
Speaker 5: have to prove intent. That is a part of obstruction of justice. But the more that we have these stories, the more it seems like intent is there. It is
Speaker 3: clear, you know, perhaps one conversation is troubling enough, but you have him calling now to intelligence.
Speaker 5: and I think you start to get into this is a person who is determined to try to stop any investigation into Michael Flynn and that is you know I think for nothing else he should understand that this would be very bad optics but that's in a best case scenario
Speaker 6: and and I have to ask you Congressman Banks because you're a veteran and in this report
Speaker 6: would essentially mean that he was ordering a uniformed Navy
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): Admiral Mike Rogers to basically tamp down an investigation. What do you make of that?
Well, if these
Speaker 8: allegations are true, this would be a pattern of a number of troubling allegations. But I think Republicans and Democrats
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): are unified on Capitol Hill to support the Mueller investigation, his independence, his integrity that he's brought, and credibility that he's brought to the investigation, along with the congressional investigations
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): House and the Senate. Let's let those investigations do their work, their due diligence before we make irrational statements about anything further than that. I'm content in allowing the investigations to work their
way through
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): the process.
Speaker 10: So you see, if these allegations are true, but then what? What do you mean by that? If? What if they are true? Well, if
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): they are, then we need to take action and deal with them appropriately. If not,
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): And what would that action be? What's appropriate? Well, you know, I'm content in waiting for the investigations to work through the process to make statements about what, hypothetically, what should happen following that. I think it's important and entirely appropriate for members of Congress to allow the investigations to work their way through the process before making statements about what might or might not happen hypothetically.
Speaker 4: But let me ask you this, because it gets down to what is the
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): standard here.
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): If it is proven to be true that the president of the United States called on his director of the FBI and then director of two of the intelligence agencies and told them to stop
an active
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): investigation, would that to you, let's forget the legal terminology for a
Speaker 1: moment, obstruction of justice, but would that to you be undue interference? There's
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): no question. There's no question. These allegations are serious. They undoubtedly will be a part of Director Mueller's independent investigation.
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): as well as the investigations in the House and the Senate. But I believe it is completely responsible and appropriate for members of Congress to allow the investigations to work their way through the process before addressing hypotheticals about what comes.
Speaker 12: And that brings to the next question, because you do have this special
Speaker 6: probe, Special Counsel Robert Mueller, who is taking over the investigation. I was talking to one official who said, you know,
It's
Speaker 6: concerned on his part that you have these two investigations on Capitol Hill where
Speaker 14 (higher-pitched voice): they're calling witnesses to testify, including James Comey, and how that could sort of interfere with what he's trying to do. How is
this
Speaker 15: going to work? It is a challenging situation. We saw just a tiny hint of it when Rod Rosenstein came
Speaker 3: and spoke to us in the classified briefing. There wasn't much that was classified there, but I would say that one of the things that was very frustrating to many of us in the room was when we were just trying to get information about why he wrote the memo. Why?
Speaker 3: When did he write the memo? Why did he write the memo? Did he just wake up one day and say, hey, it'd be great to write a memo? Or did somebody actually come to him and ask him to write it? If that was the case, did he know that it was going to be used in a way? You didn't get satisfying answers to those questions. He didn't answer any of those questions, and he directed that.
Speaker 3: to the fact that Mueller is going to be doing the investigation. We need to wait. But there are competing priorities here. Not competing priorities, but there are parallel priorities. Let's say that. That Congress has an oversight authority. We should be able to continue to investigate as this goes forward. And while it's true that we want to wait for the facts to emerge, we can't afford to wait a long
Speaker 5: time, particularly with
Speaker 5: story after story emerging this latest news I think
is is
Speaker 5: extremely distressing
Speaker 16: and of course
Speaker 17: another big headline that came out today is the fact that that Michael Flynn Flynn will
Speaker 6: invoke his Fifth Amendment rights in response to subpoenas from the Senate Intelligence Committee this is what President Trump said during the campaign about those who take the fifth let's
listen
Speaker 18: here's people taking the Fifth
Amendment
Speaker 19: four people plus
Speaker 19: the guy who illegally did the server. You know, he put it in the illegal server. So there are five people taking the Fifth Amendment, like you see
Speaker 20: on the mob, right? You see the mob takes the Fifth Amendment.
If you're
Speaker 20: innocent, why are you taking the Fifth Amendment?
Okay, so
Speaker 14 (higher-pitched voice): Congressman Banks, if General Flynn is innocent, why is he taking the Fifth?
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): Well, I can't say or defend it.
not he
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): is innocent but that again will be a part of the investigation
Speaker 21: what do you make of the fact he's taken the
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): fifth it's troubling and it's it's a part of a troubling series of of uh of actions by by mr flynn and uh it it it it again uh foreshadows i think a troubling pattern of behavior that we've seen in recent weeks i want to
Speaker 22: ask about your because of course we've heard many
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): democrats in public criticize the president's behavior here it's only in the last week or two
were I
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): speaking to
you?
Speaker 2 (lower-pitched voice): of folks on the Hill, Republicans who at least privately, some publicly, but many more privately who say, listen, this is getting to a different level. Wide-eyed was the way one Republican lawmaker described it to me last week. Do you sense a change in the last week or two about the level of concern from inside your own caucus? A
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): concern in whether or not we will fulfill an agenda that we all set out to fulfill at the beginning of the Congress. I ran for Congress last year. I'm a freshman on Capitol Hill to address the big issues of the day and as we get caught up in the
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): frenzy over each breaking news item from day to day related to the administration, it is
Speaker 23: definitely a distraction from our ability to do that. But is it
Speaker 1: more of a distraction? Are you becoming concerned and other fellow
Speaker 22: Republicans concerned that the president did something here that requires a remedy, right, that may have crossed a line?
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): Again, it's irresponsible to say too much more without allowing the investigation to work its way through the process. That's why I believe it's important to allow Director Mueller to do his work, allow the congressional committees to do their work before speaking anything, saying anything further about what hypothetically should come next.
Speaker 7 (higher-pitched voice): So, Congresswoman, this could take a while for these investigations to wrap up. What would you like to see in the meantime?
Speaker 24: Well, I think we would like to see, you know, each of these roles has a slightly different charge, a special
Speaker 3: prosecutor special counsel has a different charge we have also been calling for an independent commission sort of like a 9/11 commission that would be made up of citizens that could actually look at this what's happening not only in the short term but in the long term and then we would like to have the information right away around the memos around some of the answers and you know I think it's a little bit more than a distraction I really do I I understand the challenges of trying
to implement
Speaker 3: an agenda for the majority party but we're talking about the sanctity of our democracy and to me that is that's really what's at stake here so it's more than a distraction it is deeply concerning to to the future of our country in the future
of our democracy